goodmorning goodmorning periscopes
periscopes let's go on Twitter wait for
a few people to get in here
yo yo what's up vanilla gorilla its what
actually in the car yeah we're gonna go
to the car got a car in a minute sweet
sweet what up people is key to the rav4
I gotta flip you around
I've been up early this morning I've
been doing some some unsupervised
machine learning trying to pose Nets
something named Jack check it out that's
ad it's distance the sky is really far
away rav4 is coming this week let's go
for a drive check it out
I'm running for mayor San Francisco this
is my plant
my plan is nice and we're to do housing
transportation and Parks
so Ed Lee watch out I'm coming for you
actually not gonna launch a Prius
because his little bug we can do one car
at a time but we have the Prius pretty
much ready to go as well got my keys
let's head out all right so let me
switch you the other camera
here is our rav4 rav4 torque is amazing
man alright let's see what we got here
is my Aeon and of course when you buy a
neon it only comes to the shipper Plus
this Eon has been modified internally
through an open pilot here's our panda
see if that's on it's pretty on to me
and though he has a wire unfortunately
with the Toyota oh this is this is a
toyota draft by the way unfortunately
with the Toyota there's no power
consistently on this connector Oh Joe so
we've connected this guy just down we
could chase it down to the OBD port cool
so this thing up the key right here yes
we are hiring oh yeah check out our
check out our positions link for our
main website comedy eye or you can go to
our and turn off the camera review
because I have a real review mirror look
at that look at that mr. Rio rear view
mirror pretty cool right
um no we don't remove the rearview
mirror anymore we use a GoPro mount you
see this GoPro mount up here yeah this
is neon alright let's start her up
cool always keep your hands on the wheel
if you're ready to take over anytime of
course that's a good
like Miley Cyrus or some ish all right
um
cool so I'm going to take us out to the
highway and once we're engaged
thank you I'm gonna put this I wish
there was a nice way to show the guys
open pilot while I'm driving but I will
show you once we get to the highway
what up yo in the seat of my rav4
plugged in down there to the viewport we
got that wire you don't really need the
wire because you can get power when it
started but alright let's head out here
office still be on the torque limit of
even the height or graph for me I'll
spin you guys back around as soon as I
made this turn
busca now a bad connection that's too
bad
let's hope it comes back yeah the
cellphone reception here isn't the best
yeah so that's why we have a so we have
a fan the fan can run at any time so it
should keep it pretty cool pretty cool
though I hear this will make special
frequencies you can transmit on alright
this is probably good let's engage here
we go
system is driving
got the speed here
pretty cool guys pretty cool
all right so sometimes we have a fusion
issue with parked cars but this one
looks pretty good
remember always pay attention at all
times now now unfortunately the rav4 has
an issue where below 20 miles an hour
will come to a full stop so that was
totally the car but now the speeds too
low so the system cancels but it will
bring you to a full stop it actually
should hold you behind the other car for
a little bit so this is a release
candidate of open piled zero point three
point eight point two which should be
going live on Tuesday so yeah
unfortunately I have to step on the
brake right now the system could hold
you in brake but it can't really eight
this is a limitation of the car there's
just nothing you can really do about it
once you go below twenty if you send the
command the accelerate command it
doesn't accelerate this is of course
fixable with a firmware update mind
going landscape you and go landscape
let's go landscape turn this guy here to
[Music]
actually hang on
interpretation oh yeah so you could do
it with a firmware update now that
firmware update I feel a whole lot
better about because this is probably
gonna be a disengagement here this turns
pretty steep
all right I have to add to help it at
the end there so we do the Toyota has a
much much higher torque limit than the
Civic which is cool
in fact it's so much that we limit it so
if you see if you go to the Panda repo
we've already committed the safety code
for Toyotas got a cutout here got a
cutout cars coming to a stop we are good
yeah buddy
all right so you're gonna see it's gonna
say like speed to allow in a minute yeah
so okay see it says take control resume
driving manually yeah that's that's just
the limitation of the car
yes SPT law wouldn't wanted to
accelerate they're disengaged you'll get
a little bit of acceleration from creep
but we can't actually command any
acceleration video is now sideways what
do you mean by that fixing that well so
yeah I feel very differently about
firmware updates to the ECU versus
firmware updates to the steering
computer so firm updates to the ECU is
something modders have already done for
a long amount for of her for a while so
anyone who's doing life like engine
boost mods are reflashing the firmware
on their ECU much much safer because
what's the worst your ECU can do is
accelerate your car I steer controller
can do bad things you gotta be super
super careful if you're flashing them
yeah
so take control resume driving man you
need Civic firmware well but the Civic
firmware you want is like I talked about
you want the at a steering mod will sync
will see we have it but you know careful
but yeah the mod to make this car work
and stop and go is definitely doable of
course the system does not ship stop and
go the Prius can do stop and go looks
pretty well and rain yeah I'm you were
training on rain right our system
doesn't even like it doesn't you know to
be honest
here we go zu wheel legs pilot bros open
pilot whoo Dean scream man
Dean's great acceleration is a little
bit palsy which isn't great working on
that hopefully we'll have a fix before
we go live at the lodge
look at that smooth stopping that was
nice vision only no it's using a radar
iPhone X yeah I bought one of those you
know picking it up the first day one of
the first yawns be shipped um yeah I'm
picking up best I said extra hundred
dollars when getting that the first day
uh any vault update uh you know the
vault is the vault is a community car
emergent in and payout the bounty but as
far as like priorities go Toyotas our
vision what do you mean by demo vision I
tell you the new Subaru people I tell
you I tell you what what what we're
gonna have to do you show me it driving
with it with a joystick and I will work
on vision for you guys but I've yet to
see any super people drive a Subaru with
a joystick so you all don't need vision
only cruise control until I see that
all right just a second
almost to the highway
man this thing is good
so this is all the car I'll tell you
guys we had one disengagement back now
in this sharp turn and now we have a
speed to loan cancellation if you're
below 20 you can only break you can't
accelerate due to issues with the PCM
ignoring India question what's the India
question I'm not ignoring your questions
where am I going going this way no I'm
just out testing this you know your uh
release candidate you don't go get
doughnuts you know I love doughnuts
how much for your old iPhone my
beautiful iPhone 7 no no I won't have
new model same model the model team soon
someday soon
yeah I know there's these issues with
this model someday soon new models
alright let's go for a drive Leiter is
becoming cheap yeah envisions becoming
really really good let's go visit Andy
come on you under drive to Berkeley I
can auto turn right turn right right now
thank you thank you I love my interview
I was right after
we gotta cut in here
VAM you know I'm a vim guy come on you
really think I'm an eMac sky look at
this yeah look at that torque that's not
even torque man yeah we're gonna will
take Route one I'll show you guys some
real some real driving the Toyota has a
much better torque limit on the Honda so
we can we could show off some real it's
real turns doing windy roads last night
yeah Toyota tour club is actually so
high that we limit the steering tour so
we've always limited the acceleration
and deceleration but we don't you look
at the torque we limit the torque rate
so it takes one point five seconds to
ramp up full torque and that's how I can
feel safe driving
you know without a hand necessarily
touching the steering wheel because I
know that the car can't jerk me around
right
but what model you're up for anything
that has TSS P so we're gonna support
all Toyotas with DSS P
damn this thing is good all right some
adaptation lanes here notice those beeps
to disengage I love this guy's blind
spot awareness senses
system back on
whoa look at that turn get it car
all right so gonna take Route one here
not good angle
right a little fast on this term see if
we can do it
that's the kind of stuff don't like and
the Civic cannot do it maybe in the rav4
can him do it oh yeah
speed see right there on the thing
I'm gonna get on spelling over there but
I didn't
that turn man look at that turn
can you input the destination not quite
yet all right I'm gonna put you guys in
the holder my hands a little bit closer
to the wheel because it is this putting
some real torque on the wheel for these
turns good
yes so remember this is a level two
system pay attention at all times it's
like a seven-year-old driving a car but
man notice engagements here unreal
unreal
Toyota's a cool man
how many nvidia gpus v 23 in our
basement
eta for going level free oh man looks is
all open pilot driving right now look at
that look at that cutting a little on
that Lane but still totally what I would
consider safe driving
oh yeah
I spin us around here take us back I
didn't charge my phone last night
actually have 20% battery how can this
work without radar yeah if we have radar
why not use it
this is me back in control of the car
now
well pilot can't do too much city stuff
I mean it can do that system
yeah you know the sex of man gonna stop
at Safeway get some doughnuts
[Music]
Yeah right this place pretty cool place
to test off from cars
training in GTA is pretty good
alright let's put it back on
I like
now these turns are something the Civic
would be think about doing the rav4 is
just killing it this
finally finding or testing
the models have outstripped the torque
this is more
harsh on that turn back there there's no
limit of the torque ramping down as more
cramping
Civic cannot do this now
doing
finis spitting really say it's loud I
barely hear it
okay all right disengagement there I
think that confused because the lands
were to spread out wipers and this is
fog gross
Maps totalization are on the roadmap
will compile at 0.5 you guys will see
what we have planned at 0.4 but this
today we're of course to add another
disengagement there it's a lot of fog
we are today talking about about zero
point
0.4 yeah yeah demeanor
you need to certify roads no I mean it's
dropping right now like you're watching
the feed right now if you think you
could drive a car from that feed it can
probably drive a car too
phones taking screens to work out well
what
now the fog would interfere with driving
a chef just get you guys over
so I'm doing weight changes here
manually just to get to the lane that
goes back to my house
re-engagement areas too
why not certify lanes didi
safe
sure how much of Apollo is use
so you come a little bit further first
the big problem of the pole or two is
the car they support nobody yes nobody
has that data's B car is super expensive
dear
that's why we support the Toyota rav4
which for a short period of time was the
third most popular car sold in America
so this is still open pilot here
[Music]
it's a comparative tussles this is on
par with autopilot probably now I had to
correct it there to make sure you wanted
to go the other way
speed down a bit here down
ah does the modeling issues in driving
into direct Sun direct direct Sun yes
but things that might trip up some other
systems no because of how we train it
well it's important Nissan Pathfinder no
Nissan support right now Honda's and
Toyota's Toyota's are gonna be the
Bast's the Toyota Prius is the flagship
model of this year the advantage to the
Prius over the rav4 is we can do full
stop and go where in the rav4 you have
to manually accelerate once you get
below 20 miles an hour
20 the resume resume should set a clue
speed to 45
marks
I think of X Matic seamanship anything
yeah
I'll believe it when they ship it
open Tyler can do stop and go the Prius
and civic can Nissan Pathfinder is
definitely not in the top ten for the
u.s. there is a Nissan in there the
Nissan Rogue is in bigger I'm so three
or pickups through your Honda store your
Toyotas and there's the Nissan Rogue
right I think that's a pretty good name
for the one River jump says autopilot
driving right now the Toyota can also
turn the wheel all the way down to zero
speed which the Civic camps and the ILX
can't
but the Prius really is gonna be the
best car because you'll get full stop
and go and add full steering that's why
the Prius is the flagship for the year
but this one is coming up first
that might be it it might not be a
flagship for next year it might just be
those six Hondas and Toyotas
it's traffic sites
oh well traffic light no no no traffic
lights no shipping system today could be
a traffic lights or stop signs
0.5 that's that's that's when the
mapping efforts will really start to
take off that was a disengagement right
there and you do hear that noise the
brake controllers making it does not
seem too happy to be stopped